ILGWU Broadside Collection 5780/109
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Broadside Collection
1907-1980
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/109
5.33 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Records (documents), broadsides.
This collection consists of broadsides created or collected by the International Ladies Garment Workers Union.
5508340
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 22, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: All 5780 Collections
Women's clothing industry--New York (State)--New York; Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York; Clothing trade--New York (State)--New York; Industrial relations--New York (State)--New York; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5508340
- Action Committee, ILGWU. Action Committee for week work and one (fighting) union, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Federation of Labor, 1914-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  1914, 1925
- American Cloak and Manufacturers Association (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Undated.
- Anarchist Workers Group, 1922-1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  1922, 1925, 1927-28
- Anti-Nazi and Fascist Committee of Twenty-Five of the ILGWU. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Baltimore Area (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Boston Joint Board. affiliated bodies, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Boston Joint Board. affiliated bodies, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Buffalo, N.Y., 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Campaign Committee. ILGWU, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Campaign Committee (Finishers Trade Union Club) Local 9, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Centerist Groups, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Central Committee (of all) Left Wing Groups in the ILGWU, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Chicago Joint Board and affiliated bodies, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Cincinnati (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cleveland Joint Board. Local 195 and affiliated bodies, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cloak Committee of 100. Cloak Department of the Industrial Union, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cloak and Dress Pressers Left Wing Local 35, ILGWU, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cloak and Dressmakers Misc. Group, 1916-1933 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  1916, 1925-27, 1933
- Cloak and Dress Pressers Social Aid League, Local. 35, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Cloak and Dress Shop Chairmens Council, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Cloak and Dressmakers Left Wing Groups of the ILGWU, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  1931, 1933
- Cloak and Dressmakers (United) Progressive League, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Cloak, Dress, Rain Coat Makers and Ladies Tailors (Madison, Wisconsin), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 23a)
- Cloak Operators Mutual Aid Club, 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  1930-31, 1933
- Cloakmakers Left Wing Groups of Local 1, ILGWU, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Cloak Shop Chairmens Committee, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Cloak, Suit and Manufacturers of New York, United, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Cloakmakers Center, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Cloakmakers Left Wing Groups, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Cloakmakers Shop Delegates League, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Cloakmakers Unemployment Council, Cloakmakers United Action Committee, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Cloakmakers United Front Committee, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Committee for Preservation of the Trade Unions, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Committee of Action Elected at the Conference for Week Work and One Class Struggle Union in the Cloak Trade, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Committee of Fifty, 1924-1932 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  1924, 1927-28, 1932
- Committee of Ten and Twenty-Five, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  1929, 1932
- Communist Party, General, 1923-1953 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  1923, 1925-27, 1930, 1933-34, 1936, 1938-40, 1943-44, 1953
- Communist Party (War Effort), 1938-1943 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  1938, 1941-43
- Communist Party (Front Organizations), 1938-1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  1938, 1940-46
- Concert Programs, 1938-1974 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Connecticut (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Conventions, 1928-1950 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  1928, 1940, 1947, 1950
- Cotton Garment Workers, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Decatur, Illinois (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Dress and Waist Manufacturers Assn., NY, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Expelled Members (Box 1, Folder 46)
- David Dubinsky, 1939-1976 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  1939, 1949, 1957, 1976
- Education Dept., ILGWU, 1925-1946 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  1925-26, 1928, 1935, 1939-40, 1944-46
- Education Dept., ILGWU, 1925-1941 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  1925-29, 1940-41
- Firms (literature from workers, Union and firm), 1915-1959 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  1915, 1925, 1928, 1933, 1938, 1959
- Furriers Union, 1927-1947 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  1927, 1935-38, 1940-41, 1946-47
- Furriers Union, 1920-1939 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  1920, 1936-39
- General Executives Board and Presidents Office, 1926-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  1926-29, 1933-35
- General Strike Committee of the ILGWU of Locals 2, 3, 9,10, 23, 48, 64 and 82, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Hourwich, Isaac A. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Infants and Childrens Wear Association, Inc., United, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- ILGWU General, 1912-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  1912, 1923, 1925, 1927, 1929, 1935, 1938, 1949, 1951, 1970, 1977, 1980
- Italian-American Labor Council, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Italian Dressmakers, Italian Progressive Comm. L. 48 and 89, Italian Trade Union Progressive Committee, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Joint Action Committee, Locals 2, 9, and 22. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Undated. Joint Committee of Action, Locals 2,9, & 22
- Joint Defense (and Relief Committees), 1927 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Justice, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Labor Stage, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Left Wing Groups. General, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Left Wing Groups. ILGWU, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Left Wing Groups of the Cloak Locals, ILGWU, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Left Wing Group Cloak Operators Local 1, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Left Wing Group, Local 1, 9..., 22... and 35, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Left Wing Group, Local 9, 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  1931-32, 1934-35, 1937
- Left Wing Group, Local 35, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Left Wing Group of Local 1, 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Local Elections (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Local 1, Election Ballots (and Slates) from all local groups, 1922-1934 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  1922, 1930-31, 1933-34
- Local 1, Cloak and Suit Operators Union, 1922-1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  1922-24, 1931-35
- Local 2, Cloak, Suit and Reefer Operators, 1914-1929 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  1914, 1924-25, 1927-28, 1929
- Local 2, Election Ballots (and Slates) from all local groups, 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  1925-26, 1928
- Local 2, United Cloak and Skirt Makers Union, Philadelphia, Pa. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Local 3, Sample Makers, Ladies Tailors, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Local 9, Committees for Week Work and One Fighting Union (Action Comm., Comm. of 50), 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Local 9, Cloak and Suit Finishers, and general groups in Local 9, 1912-1934 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  1912, 1925, 1928, 1930-34
- Local 9, Trade Union Groups (Progressive and United), 1930-1937 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  1930-32, 1934, 1937
- Local 10, all groups and factions. [folder 1 of 2], 1924-1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  1924-25, 1927-28, 1933-35, 1940, 1944, 1947, 1949
- Local 10, all groups and factions. [folder 2 of 2], 1924-1949 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Local 11, Cloakmakers Union (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Local 17, Reefer Makers Union, 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  1924-25, 1929
- Local 22, all groups and factions, 1931-1942 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  1931-33, 1934-35, 1937, 1942
- Local 22, Dressmakers Union, 1925-1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  1925, 1927, 1931, 1933-35, 1937, 1942, 1944, 1947, 1956, 1965
- Local 22, all groups and factions, 1932-1948 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  1932-34, 1937, 1944, 1947, 1948
- Local 33 and 34, Corset Workers & Corset Cutters, Los Angeles, California, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Local 22, Dressmakers-Programs, 1935-1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  1935, 1943-44, 1947-48, 1957
- Local 22, all groups and factions. [folder 1 of 2], 1934-1942 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  1934-37, 1939-40, 1942
- Local 22, all groups and factions. [folder 2 of 2], 1934-1942 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Local 23-25, 1959-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  1959-62, 1975
- Local 35, Pressers Union, and other Local 35 groups, 1922-1933 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  1922, 1925-31, 1933
- Local 38, Ladies Tailors, Theatrical Costume and Alteration Workers, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Local 48, Italian Cloakmakers, 1949-1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  1949, 1966
- Local 49, Ladies Waist and Dressmakers Union, Boston (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Local 50, Waist and Dressmakers, Philadelphia (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Local 60, Dress Pressers and other Local 60 Groups, 1939-1963 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  1939, 1949, 1953-54, 1959, 1963
- Local 62, White Goods Workers Union. [folder 1 of 2], 1921-1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  1921, 1923-35, 1941, 1949
- Local 62, White Goods Workers Union. [folder 2 of 2], 1921-1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Local 65, Cloak and Dressmakers, Los Angeles (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Local 66, Bonnaz Embroidery Workers, 1908-1940 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  1908, 1932-33, 1940
- Local 72, Dressmakers Union, Toronto (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Local 76, White Goods Workers Union, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Local 89, Italian Dressmakers, 1936-1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  1936-37, 1947-50, 1953, 1965
- Local 91, Childrens Dress, 1925-1938 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  1925, 1933, 1937-38
- Local 102, Cloak and Dress Drivers & Helpers Union, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Local 117, Cloak, Suit, Infants and Childrens Coat OperatorUnion. [folder 1 of 3], 1922-1950 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  1922, 1931, 1936-40, 1943-44, 1946- 50
- Local 117, Cloak, Suit, Infants and Childrens Coat OperatorUnion. [folder 2 of 3], 1922-1950 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Local 117, Cloak, Suit, Infants and Childrens Coat OperatorUnion. [folder 3 of 3], 1922-1950 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Local 130, Coat and Suit Workers Union, New Jersey, 1949-1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  1949, 1965
- Local 132, Plastic, Metal and Novelty Workers Union (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Local 134, Coat and Suit Workers Union, Paterson, New Jersey, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Local 135, Coat and Suit Workers Union, Newark, New Jersey, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Ladies Neckwear Workers Union, 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Local 144, Dressmakers Union, Newark, New Jersey, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Local 155, Knitgoods Workers Union, 1934-1948 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  1934, 1940, 1944, 1948
- Local 165, Cloakmakers Union, Newburgh, New York, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Local 184, Dressmakers Union, Seattle, Washington, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Local 266, Los Angeles, California (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Local 328, Kokomo, Indiana, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Local 384, McAlester, Oklahoma, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Local 385, Salt Lake City, Utah (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Los Angeles Joint Board and affiliated bodies, 1920-1942 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  1920, 1940-42
- Los Angeles, 1920-1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  1920, 1939, 1950
- May Day Committee, 1932-1939 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  1932-33, 1939
- Merchant Ladies Garment Association, Inc., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Montreal (affiliated bodies), 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  1937, 1940-42
- Mooney, Tom and Warren K. Billings, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Mutual Aid Club, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- National Organization Committee, Cloak and Dressmakers Joint Board, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Nazism, Fascism - (anti), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Needle Trades Workers Campaign Committee, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union (Joint Board Cloak, Dress and Furriers Union), 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union, 1924-1934 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  1924, 1928-34
- Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union (Cloak and Dress Departments), 1930-1933 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Needle Trades Workers Unity League, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- New Jersey, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- New York Cloak and Dressmakers Union Joint Board. [folder 1 of 3], 1921-1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  1921, 1924-30, 1958
- New York Cloak and Dressmakers Union Joint Board. [folder 2 of 3], 1921-1958 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- New York Cloak and Dressmakers Union Joint Board. [folder 3 of 3], 1921-1958 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- New York Cloak Pressers Welfare Soc., Inc., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- New York Cloak, Suit, Skirt and Reefer Makers Union, (Joint Board), 1907-1960 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  1907-08, 1913-14, 1918, 1923, 1925-27, 1929, 1932-33, 1935-36, 1940, 1947, 1960
- New York Dress and Waistmakers Union Joint Board, 1932-1958 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  1932-33, 1935-36, 1947, 1958
- New York Dress and Waistmakers Union, 1921 Strike (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Northeast Department, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  1953, 1956
- Organizing Committee, ILGWU, 1921-1927 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  1921, 1927
- Organizing Leaflets. [folder 1 of 2], 1916-1964 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  1916, 1925, 1927-28, 1933, 1935, 1937, 1941, 1964
- Organizing Leaflets. [folder 2 of 2], 1916-1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Pennsylvania, 1946-1956 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  1946, 1949, 1956
- Philadelphia Joint Board and affiliated bodies, 1925-1935 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  1925, 1927, 1935
- Political Leaflets, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Progressive Club, Local 17, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  1933, 1935
- Progressive Cutters, Local 10, 1925-1937 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  1925, 1937
- Progressive Groups, Local 10 and 35, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Progressive League of Local 1, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Progressive Pressers of Local 35, 1924-1925 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Puerto Rico (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Pure and Simple Trade Union League, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Radio Broadcast union and non-union literature, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Rank and File, ILGWU, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Rank and File Committee, Local 10, 1931-1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Rank and File Committee of ACW, ILGWU and Hat Cap and Millinery Workers (Box 5, Folder 10)
- St. Louis Joint Board, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- San Francisco Joint Board and affiliated bodies, 1934-1938 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  1934-35, 1938
- Shop Chairmen Council (Cloak and Dressmakers), 1927 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Shop Delegate Propaganda Committee, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Shop Delegates League, 1921-1922 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Social Friends Club (Local 9) and the Committee of 25, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Socialist Party (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Socialist Workers Party (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Southeastern Region, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Southwestern Region, 1936-1942 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  1936, 1942
- Tolerance ( and Solidarity) Groups, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Toronto Joint Board and affiliated locals, 1928-1976 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Trade Union Center Groups (Local 1), 1930-1934 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  1930-32, 1934
- Trade Union Committee to Manufacture Clothing for Spain (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Trade Union Educational League, 1922-1929 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  1922-1926, 1929
- Trade Unionist Groups (Locals 2, 9, 22, 35), 1930 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Training Institute, ILGWU, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Unemployment Committee of the Left Wing Groups, ILGWU (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Union Label Department, 1967-1976 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  1967-68, 1970-72, 1976
- Union Label Department, 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  1960-61, 1969
- Unions (and general labor matters), 1933-1950 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  1933-37, 1940, 1945-46, 1949-50
- United Active and Progressive Trade Union Center, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- United Campaign Committee of All the Progressive Elements, Locals of Cloakmakers Union, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- United Dressmakers Committee, Left Wing and Active Members Groups, Local 22, 1925-1935 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  1925, 1935
- United Front Committees, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  Cloakmakers, Conference, & 100
- United Progressive League, 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  1930-31, 1933. Incl. Cloakmakers & Dressmakers
- United Progressive League. Local 1, 1931-1934 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- United Progressive Trade Union Center, (Local 1), 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- United Trade Unionist, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Unity Committee. Joint Board Cloak and Dressmakers Union, Joint Board, Furriers Union, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Unity House, 1918-1968 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  1918, 1927, 1929-30, 1935-36, 1948, 1952-53, 1956, 1962, 1968
- WEVD (Union Assembly) (Box 5, Folder 42)
- With These Hands (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Womens Trade Union League (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Loose materials. (Box 6)
  Dates unknown.
- Broadsides (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Heckers Flour - advertisements, broadsides, ad ideas (Box 8, Folder 1)
- American Cancer Society - Advertisements, Broadsides, Photos, negatives (Box 8, Folder 2)
- ILGWU advertisement (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Assorted advertisements for ILGWU (Box 8, Folder 4)
- ILGWU Mother's Day Advertisement (Box 8, Folder 5)
- ILGWU Advertisement (Box 8, Folder 6)
- ILGWU Advertisement (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Assorted ILGWU Advertisements (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Labor Day Advertisement for ILGWU (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Labor Day Advertisements for ILGWU (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Broadsides (Box 8, Folder 11)
- ILGWU broadsides (Box 10)
  - A Mass=Meeting for the Ladies Tailors of Brooklyn will be given by the Ladies Branch, Loc. 16, U.G.W. of A.: ILGWU Broadside, 1897 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - By Order of the General Executive Board, International Ladies Garment Workers Union; Ladies Waist and Dressmakers!: ILGWU Broadside, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The New Post / Issued by the Joint Board of the Cloak and Shirt Makers Union of New York: ILGWU Broadside, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The General Strike Periodical / Issued by the Cloak & Shirt Makers Union of Phila., 1914 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Strike declared poster (Box 11)
  - Strike declared poster (Box 11, Folder 1)
- ILGWU posters (Box 12)
  - ILGWU union label posters (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Text digitized from the collection. (Box 13)